Guide to the Garden Club of Allegheny County Records, 1913-2012 AIS.2006.07
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Garden Club of Allegheny County Records
1913-2012
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Garden Club of Allegheny County
AIS.2006.07
42.3 Linear Feet (84 boxes)
This collection documents the functions and activities undertaken by the Garden Club of Allegheny County (GCAC), a chapter of the Garden Club of America. The material, dating between 1913-2012, includes organizational records such as board and membership meeting minutes, official club reports, publications, events, correspondence, and club ephemera.
History
The Garden Club of Allegheny County (GCAC) was founded in 1914 by a group of civic-minded women interested in the benefits of public and private gardening. The GCAC is committed to its mission of promoting knowledge of horticulture, interest in conservation and historic preservation, environmental education and civic planning and planting programs throughout Allegheny County. The club's preamble to the first meeting states its mission is "...to promote an interest in gardens, their design and management; to cooperate with the protection of wild flowers and native plants; and to encourage civic planting." During both World Wars, the group became active in the war effort by promoting Victory Gardens, aligning with the Women's Land Army, and contributing heavily to the American Red Cross War fund.
The GCAC joined the Garden Club of America (GCA) in 1916 to become more involved with the national gardening community. The GCAC has since hosted GCA annual meetings in Pittsburgh, Pa. The GCAC's civic duties have expanded from the retention of natural beauty in urban areas to developing landscape restoration projects and protecting natural landscapes. However, the GCAC has never relinquished its commitment to civic planting and has contributed gardens to several Pittsburgh neighborhoods.
The GCAC maintains a long standing tradition with Phipps Conservatory and Botanical Gardens, a botanical garden center located in the Oakland neighborhood of Pittsburgh. The GCAC often uses Phipps Conservatory as a venue for its many flower shows. Other notable projects are the 1951 establishment of a master plan and formal rose garden in Mellon Park, along with the 1961 restoration of the kitchen garden at Old Economy Village. The GCAC shows its continued dedication to education, preservation, and the restoration of Pittsburgh gardens.
Scope and Content Notes
The Garden Club of Allegheny County (GCAC) has maintained records throughout most of their history which spans from 1913 to the present. Each series contains a scope note detailing the content found within the records. The GCAC is a chapter of the Garden Club of America and this affiliation is documented within the content of the collection. The GCAC collection contains official minutes, reports, publications, photographs, and newspaper clippings.
In March 2011, GCAC donated additional materials relating to the organization. Included were board meeting minutes, committee reports, photographs of members at various events, and many additional files on the Pizzazz event. Likewise in 2013, additional material arrived and was subsequently processed. In both cases these additions are noted as new series at the end of the collection.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into eight series:
Series I. Minutes, 1914-2007
Series II. Reports, 1914-2008
Series III. Events, 1914-2009
Series IV. Publications, 1914-2009
Series V. Correspondence, 1920-2006
Series VI. Ephemera and Media Material, 1914-2007
Series VII. 2011 Additions, 1961-2010
Series VIII. 2013 Additions, 1934-2012
Access Restrictions
Membership lists, rosters and directories of the Garden Club of Allegheny County dating from 1946 to the present are not available to researchers. The following boxes or folders are therefore restricted: Box 17 > Folders 3, 6-9, 11-13 and 16; Box 45 > Folders 11-15, 17-18 and 20-23; Box 46 > All folders.
Accruals
Additional material was acquired in April 2008, March 2011 and August 2012. Further accruals are expected.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Garden Club of Allegheny County on April 11, 2006.
Previous Citation
Garden Club of Allegheny County Records, 1913-2012, AIS.2006.07, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Records of the Garden Club of Allegheny County, 1913-2005, AIS 200607, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh.
Related Material
Charlotte Cohen Collection Related to Gardening, 1950-2002, AIS.2005.05, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Ralph E. Griswold, GWSM, Inc. Collection, 1912-1988, AIS.2001.10, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Historic Landscape Survey of Allegheny County Records, 1970-2002, AIS.2005.01, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Ezra C. Stiles Collection, 1916-1953, AIS.2000.08, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Clippings (Information artifacts); Photographs; Annual reports; Civil service; Community gardens -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Landscape architecture -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Parks -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Gardening -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Gardening -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Allegheny County (Pa.); Sewickley (Pa.); Environment; Japan; Architecture; Hawaii; Societies; Philadelphia (Pa.); Women; Minutes (Administrative records); Battles, Marjorie Gibbon; Chestnut Hill Garden Club; Childs, Elizabeth D. Littell; Dicky, Catherine Colt; Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania; Garden Club of Allegheny County; Garden Club of America; Gates, Millicent Anne; Holgate, Jeanne; Hunt, J., Mrs.; Hunt, Roy Arthur; Hunt, Rachel McMasters Miller; Klay, Sharon; Pontefract, J. G., Mrs.; Rea, Margaret Pollard; Richardson, Rosamound Fitch; Richardson, R., Mrs.; Sewickley Horticultural Society (Pa.); Women's Land Army of America; Women's National Farm and Garden Association; Phipps Conservatory
- Minutes, 1914-2007; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains the official board of director's minutes, regular meeting minutes, general meeting notes and Zone V meeting notes and information. Meeting minutes include descriptions and meeting dates, times, locations, hostesses, speakers, and agendas. This series is divided into four subseries: Regular Membership Meeting Minutes, Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, General Meeting Records and Reports and Zone V Meeting Material. The material in this series date from 1914 to 2007.
  - Regular Membership Meeting Minutes, 1914-2007; 1.
    The earlier membership meeting minutes were kept in binders with each meeting numbered and in chronological order from the first meeting at the residence of President Mrs. Frances H. Denny, Springfield Farm, in Sewickley Heights on October 30, 1914. The minutes are set up with official minutes interspersed with ephemeral objects such as programs, invitations, and pamphlets which are glued between the pages of typed minutes. The later membership meeting minutes are stapled together and are also interspersed with ephemeral object. All minutes are typed and signed by the respective club secretary of that time and provide insight into the overall management and activities of the garden club.
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1914-1923 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1926-1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1926-1939 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1953-1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1965-1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1976-1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Membership Meeting Minutes, 2005-2007; (CD) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1926-2007; 2.
    The Board of Directors meeting minutes document the proceedings of Board of Directors private meetings. They are mainly typed, but the earliest are hand written. The Board of Directors meeting minutes typically cover two to three issues per meeting and usually focus on budgetary items, future speakers and activities.
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1926-1941 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1941-1946 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1946-1954 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1955-1962 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1962-1967 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1967-1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1972-1977 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1978-1983 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - General Meeting Records and Reports, 1914-1974; 3.
    The General Meeting records and reports are a culmination of annual meetings, directories, newspaper clippings, flower show announcements, and invitations. These reports directly relate to the General Meeting Records. The reports also reflect amendments and changes in the meeting and policy books. The meeting book, along with the policy book (found under Constitution and By-laws), contain general procedures for conducting meetings and were consulted during general meetings to confirm any questions concerning by-laws and voting procedures.
    - General Meeting Records and Reports, 1914-1934 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - General Meeting Records and Reports, 1914-1934 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - General Meeting Records and Reports, 1923-1926 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - General Meeting Records and Reports, 1934-1939 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - General Meeting Records and Reports, 1940-1942 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - General Meeting Records and Reports, 1943-1946 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - General Meeting Records and Reports, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Zone V Meeting Material, 1953-2006; 4.
    Zone V meeting material contains notes, information and material about the regional meetings. Also included is information about Zone V's Presidents Council meetings.
    - Central Eastern Zone Meeting, 1953 & 1962 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - From Private Spaces to Public Places, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Zone V Business Meeting, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Zone V Meeting, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Zone V Meeting, 1953 & 1956 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Zone V Meeting, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Zone V Meeting, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Zone V Meeting, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Zone V Meeting, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Zone V Meeting, 1979, 1981, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Zone V Meeting, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Zone V Meeting, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Zone V Meeting, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Zone V Meeting, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Zone V Meeting, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Zone V Meeting and Travel, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Zone V Meeting Rotation, 1980-1989 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Zone V Mini-Meeting, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Zone V Presidents Council Meeting, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Zone V Presidents Council Meeting, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Zone V Presidents Council Meeting, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Reports, 1914-2008; II.
  This series contains annual official meeting reports, treasurer's reports, and committee reports. This series also includes material for reports on horticulture and conservation education. This series is divided into five subseries: Annual Meeting Reports, Treasurer's Reports, Membership Reports, Committee Reports and President's Reports.
  - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1922-2008; 1.
    Annual reports are prepared for the annual meeting of both GCA and GCAC. The information in the reports provides a recap and review of that year's meetings, activities, member announcements, and special events. Included in the records are funding issues, dues, and a year-end activity report.
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1938-1939 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1947-1949 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1947-1953 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1951-1952 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1955-1956 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1960-1961 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1996-1997 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1997-1998 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1997-1998 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1998-1999 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 1999-2000 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 2001-2002 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 2002-2003 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Annual Meeting and Reports, 2007-2008 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1914-2007; 2.
    The Treasurer's Reports include meeting minutes, budget proposals and financial information. The reports show the financial activities and status of the GCAC.
    - Treasurer's Reports, Notebook, 1916-1944 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1914-1920 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1921-1930 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1931-1943 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1954-1959 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1970-1975 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1975-1980 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1983-1990 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1995-1996 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1996-1997 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1998-1999 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1999-2000 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 2001-2002 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 2004-2005 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 2006-2007 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Membership Reports, 1914-2008; 3.
    These files pertain to the selection of members, the standards that members should uphold and general information about present members.
    - Membership Reports, 1914 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Membership Reports, 1915 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Membership Reports [RESTRICTED], 1939-1999 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Membership Reports, 1950-1961 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Membership Reports, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Membership Reports [RESTRICTED], 1990 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Membership Reports [RESTRICTED], 1996-1997 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Membership Reports [RESTRICTED], 1997-1998 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Membership Reports [RESTRICTED], 1998-1999 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Membership Reports, 1999-2000 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Membership Reports [RESTRICTED], 2003 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Membership Reports [RESTRICTED], 2004-2005 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Membership Reports [RESTRICTED], 2006-2007 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Membership Acceptance Letters, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Membership Acceptance Letters, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Membership Booklet [RESTRICTED], 2007-2008 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Membership Interviews, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Membership Standards (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Profiles of Members (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Questionnaire, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Committee Reports, 1942-2008; 4.
    This subseries documents various committee and their activities and reports. Not all committees are represented here; many of the committee reports were included in Regular Meeting Minutes, Annual Reports and the General Meeting Material.
    - Admissions and Nominating Committee, 1971-1988 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Badges and Bags Committee, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Bags Committee Meeting, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Boat Committee Meeting, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Budget and Finance, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Committee Activities, 1988-1989 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Committees and Chairpeople, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Committee Directories (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Committee Reports and Activities, 1981-1982 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Committee Reports and Notes (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Committees of the Garden Club of Allegheny County, Spring 2004 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Decorations Committee, 1984-1986 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Gardens and Hospitality Meeting, 1985-1986 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - GCA Legislative Meeting, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Handbook Committee, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Hospitality Committee, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Hotel Meeting Committee, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Information Committee, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Invitation Committee, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Joint Presidents Council, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 1988-1994 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 1989-1994 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 1997-1999 & 2003 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 1998-1999 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 2002-2003 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 2004-2005 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 2005-2006 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Long Range Planning Committee - Botanic Garden (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Long Range Planning Committee - Fern Hollow (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Long Range Planning Committee - Frick Art and Historical Center (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Long Range Planning Committee - Grow Pittsburgh (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Long Range Planning Committee - January 2006 Dinner (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Long Range Planning Committee - Hurricane Katrina Fund, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Long Range Planning Committee - Magic Penny Garden (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Long Range Planning Committee - Montour Trails Friends of the Riverfront (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Long Range Planning Committee - National Aviary (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Long Range Planning Committee - Nine Mile Run Watershed Association (Box 20, Folder 4)